Guide to the Paul Langland Papers 1926-2011 MSS 253
© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series VI: Video
  - Subseries B: Originals
    - A Voice For All, NYU ETW AIDS Week, 1991, Tape 1 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0071)
    - A Voice For All, NYU ETW AIDS Week, 1991, Tape 2 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0072)
    - Downtown Upstate, 1991 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0073)
    - Paul Langland ETW Class, 1992 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0074)
    - [1] -- Angels and Apes Trio, NYC, April 1993 [2] -- Saint Marks Church Trio, December 1993, [1] -- April, 1993 [2] -- December 1993 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0075)
    - Full Flora Smak, New York University, 1994 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0076)
    - Full Flora Smak, New York University, 1994 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0077)
    - Full Flora Smak, New York University, 1994 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0078)
    - Almost Rapture Rehersal, November 28, 1995 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0079)
    - Dybbuks and Chicken Soup, 1995 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0080)
    - Untitled Duet, Paul Langland and Brendan McCall, DanceFest 5, 1995 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0081)
    - Almost Rapture Rehersal Master, Jaunary 18, 1996, January 18, 1996 (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0216)
    - Almost Rapture, Danspace at Saint Marks Church, New York City, January 21, 1996 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0082)
    - 33 Fainting Spells, The Uninvited, On the Boards, Seattle, January 26, 1996 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0083)
      Credit: Dayna Hanson and Gaelen Hanson
    - Almost Rapture and Other Dance Surprises, 1997 Danspace Project [1]-- Normal Dog Time [2]-- Land Mind [3]-- Almost Rapture (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0217)
    - Section Seven Class Showing Choreography, March 1998 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0085)
    - [1] -- Almost Rapture, Solo [2] -- Honor, Excerpt. Dixon Place, April 28, 1998, April 1998 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0084)
    - Honor, Tisch NYU-Danspace Project Master, May 17, 1998 (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0218)
      Format: 3/4 in. Umatic TRT: unknown
    - Honor, Tisch N.Y.U. Danspace Project, 1998, May 17, 1998 (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0230)
    - Honor, Tisch N.Y.U/Danspace Project, 1998 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0086)
      TRT: 00:46:38
    - Tape 1, AW Warm Up, Cellular Introduction, Celluar Discussion, [1998] (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0219)
    - Tape 2, [1998] (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0220)
    - Tape 4, November 18, 1998 (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0221)
    - Tape 5, Four Fluid Reviews and Comp. Review, Cellular, Lymph, Int. Cell, Fascia, November 20, 1998 (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0222)
    - Tape 6, AW Wall Work and Dancing, [1998] (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0223)
    - Tape 7, CSK Duets and Solos, November 30, 1998 (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0224)
    - Tape 8, CSK AW including Scalpel, December 3, 1998 (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0225)
    - Tape 9, Venus Group Improv., [December 2] 1998 (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0226)
    - Tape 10, Synovial, Venus Duet Phrases, December 4, 1998 (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0227)
    - Tape 11, Alex on Floor, AW Standing Barr Arterial, December 7, 1998 (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0228)
    - Tape 12, Fluids Projects, Self Directed [Warm Up], December 9, 1998 (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0229)
    - Danspace Project, Silver Series: Volumer Two, Channel Z, St. Mark's Church in-the-Bowrey, March 26, 1999 (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0231)
    - 25th Anniversary Danspace Project Silver Series: Volume Two, Part 1, Channel Z, March 28, 1999 (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0232)
    - Spontaneous Combustion Cabaret, Northampton, MA, Various Acts Ending with Outtahand, [1999] (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0087)
    - Heat, Presented by Movement Research, Judson Church, New York, April 24, 2000 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0088)
    - Heat, Presented by Movement Research Judson Church, NYC, April 24, 2000 (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0233)
    - Heat, Presented by Movement Research, Judson Church, New York, April 24, 2000 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0089)
    - [1] -- Heat, Judson Church, New York, April 24, 2000 [2] -- Honor, Tisch School of Art, New York, May 17, 1998, [1] -- April 24, 2000 [2] -- May 17, 1998 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0090)
    - Jungle Breath, Dixon, May 30, 2000 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0091)
    - 7th World (Really the 6th) Danspace Project, November 30, 2000 (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0235)
    - 7th World (Really the 6th), 9th New York Improvisation Festival, DansSpace Project, December 1, 2000 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0092)
    - 7th World (Really the 6th), 9th New York Improvisation Festival, DansSpace Project, December 1, 2000 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0093)
    - 7th World (Really the 6th), 9th New York Improvisation Festival, DansSpace Project, December 1, 2000 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0094)
    - Heat, University of California Davis, April 10, 2001 (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0236)
    - Heat, University of California, Davis, April 10, 2001 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0101)
    - Heat, University of California, Davis, April 10, 2001 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0103)
    - Heat, University of California, Davis, April 10, 2001 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0102)
    - [1] -- Animas [2] -- Heat, UC Davis, April 14, 2001 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0095)
    - Getting Ready to Really Leave, Amherst College, June 16, 2001 (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0234)
    - Getting Ready to Really Leave, Amherst College, June 2001 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0096)
    - Rooms and Buildings, October 2001 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0098)
    - Scratch, IFNY 310, Danspace Project, November 29, 2001 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0099)
    - My Improv Festival Scratch, December 2001 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0100)
    - Getting Ready to Really Leave, Movement Research at Judson Church, March 18, 2002 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0104)
    - Getting Ready to Really Leave, Movement Research at Judson Church, March 18, 2002 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0105)
    - Getting Ready to Really Leave, Movement Research at Judson Church, March 18, 2002 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0106)
    - Getting Ready to Really Leave at Judson, March 18, 2002 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0107)
    - Whoopee in the Dark, University Settlement, NY, October 3-5, 2002, October 3, 2002 (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0237)
    - Whoopee in the Dark, Reflections on Powerlessness, October 3-5, 2002, October 3, 2002 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0108)
      TRT: 1:07:06
    - Self Erasure Pieces (In Progress) Rehersal Tape, 2002 (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0238)
    - Storyteller, excerpt from Whoopee in the Dark, MR at Judson, March 3, 2003 (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0239)
    - Du[c] Master for 4 Solos Excerpts, October 2003 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0097)
      Format: DV mini
    - Four Solos, Jewel Theatre, Luther College, January 9, 2004 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0109)
    - TSl, Four Solos Master, July 10, 2004 (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0240)
    - Z Boys; October 1984, 1984, 2004 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0003)
    - Z Boys, 1984, 2004 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0110)
    - Z Boys, 1984, 2004 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0112)
    - 20 Minute Black, Class Acts Title, undated (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0123)
    - Alabama, undated (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0114)
    - Allan Wayne Tape, undated (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0115)
    - Almost Rapture and Other Dances, undated (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0117)
    - Almost Rapture and Other Dances, undated (Box 437, Media ID: 253.0118)
    - Almost Rapture and Other Dances, undated (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0119)
    - Almost Rapture and Other Dance Surprises, undated (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0001)
    - Almost Rapture and Other Surprises, undated (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0120)
    - [1]-- Coffee [2]-- Trio: Angels and Apes [3]-- Trio: St Mark's Church, 1993 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0006)
    - Boomerang, undated (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0121)
    - Boomerang, Edited, undated (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0122)
    - Brendan and Paul Fuck Around, undated (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0116)
    - [Channel Z AD], undated (Box 41, Media ID: 253.0244)
      Format: VHS TRT: unknown
    - Channel Z at Pepsico, Preliminary Edit, undated (Box 41, Media ID: 253.0243)
    - Channel Z Studio Live: Ensemble, Singing, [Randy], undated (Box 41, Media ID: 253.0246)
    - [1] -- Combing the Will [2] -- Jungle Breath, undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0136)
    - [1]-- Dance in American [2]-- Beyond the Mainstream, undated (Box 41, Media ID: 253.0247)
    - Domestic Virtue, undated (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0126)
    - Domestic Virtue Master, undated (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0127)
    - Domestic Virtue Master, undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0150)
    - Domestic Virtue, Perf., undated (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0125)
    - Ellis Island, undated (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0128)
    - E.T.W Festival Day, undated (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0129)
    - Excerpts, Master, undated (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0166)
    - Four Pieces [1] -- Boomerang [2] -- Jungle Breath [3] -- Domestic Virtue [4] -- Rapture, undated (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0130)
      Participants: Jungle Breath - Daniel Lepkoff, Domestic Virtue - Barbara Hofrenning
    - Dolmen Music; April 2004/ Meredith Monk (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0005)
    - The Ghost of a Flea, PS 122, Tight Angle, undated (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0131)
    - The Ghost of a Flea, PS 122, Wide Angle, undated (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0132)
    - Helena Kolda, 11 Shorts, undated (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0133)
      Content: [1] -- Mingus [2] -- The Last Days of Marienbad [3] -- Focusing [4] -- Precarious Positions [5] -- 3 Poems by Honor Moore [6] -- Bachanalia [7] -- Fire and Water [8] -- All of Me [9] -- Ode to Manhattan [10] -- Noon Song [11] -- The Saints
    - Honda Commercial Auditions, undated (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0134)
    - I Will Not Be Sad In This World, undated (Box 41, Media ID: 253.0248)
    - [1] -- Jonah [2] -- Spectra, Brain Flow, undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0135)
    - Jungle Breath, Hillsdale, undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0137)
    - Kinetic Fairy Tale, Master, undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0138)
    - Kinetic Fairy Tale, Copy, undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0139)
    - Section 6, 2 Eyes video, April 22, undated (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0113)
    - [1] -- Lumberjack Jig [2] -- Raw Footage, undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0140)
    - Lory's Shots, Ferreri and Chinatown, undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0141)
      Format: Hi 8mm
    - [1] -- Man and Machine [2] -- Waterfall [3] -- Jonah. Tape 1 of 1, Copy, undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0143)
    - [1] -- Man and Machine [2] -- Waterfall [3] -- Jonah, undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0002)
    - Master edit, [1] -- Man and Machine [2] -- Waterfall, undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0142)
    - Master Excerpts [1]-- Blue Sail Fish [2]-- Filibuster II [3]-- Current Stream, undated (Box 41, Media ID: 253.0241)
      Format: 3/4 in Umatic
    - Master Excerpts, Channel Z [1]-- Blue Sail Fish [2]-- Filibuster II [3]-- Current Stream, undated (Box 41, Media ID: 253.0242)
    - Miguel Azcue Resume Tape, undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0144)
    - [1] -- Monk [2] -- Turtle Dreams. PBS Version, undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0145)
    - M. Monk, undated (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0055)
      Credit: Peter Greenway
    - Movement Track, Third Night, undated (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0038)
    - Naked Nude, Channel Z, undated (Box 41, Media ID: 253.0245)
    - [Normal Kansas], Act 1, undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0146)
    - Normal Kansas, Act 2, undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0147)
    - Normal Kansas, Act 3, undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0148)
    - N.Y Contact Group at Pratt - Tape 1, undated (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0009)
      Format: 1/2 inch open reel
    - N.Y. Contacters at Pratt - Tape 2, undated (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0010)
    - Paul Langland and Barbara Hofrenning Sampler, undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0149)
    - PBS/Butch, undated (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0124)
    - [Peholeton], undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0151)
    - [Psychoballet, Cuba], undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0152)
    - Rapture, undated (Box 538, Media ID: 253.0153)
      Format: Video 8mm TRT: unknown
    - Rapture, etc. Master, undated (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0007)
    - Retazos, Danza-Teatro, Cuba, undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0155)
    - Rooms and Buildings, undated (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0008)
    - Section Five, Inwood Park, Peter and Lisa Pieces, undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0156)
    - Self Erasure Work Tape, Master, undated (Box 41, Media ID: 253.0249)
    - [1] -- Sh[n]ok [2] -- Halfshell, undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0157)
    - Source Material, undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0158)
    - Paul Langland Title Tape, undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0159)
    - Transit Mass by NYU Experimental Theatre Wing, undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0160)
    - The Travelogue Series, Number 2, Act III, Chacon, undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0161)
    - The Travelogue Series, Number 4, Act II, Venice/Milan, undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0162)
    - A Woodcutters Dream, undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0163)
    - Whoppee in the Dark; October 2002 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0004)
    - Turtle Dreams at Plexus, undated (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0164)
    - TV, undated (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0165)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 41, Media ID: 253.0251)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 41, Media ID: 253.0250)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0167)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0168)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0169)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0170)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0171)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0172)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0173)
    - Z Boys, undated (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0111)
    - [Print], undated (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0174)
      Format: Film
    - Emotional Corridors, undated (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0175)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0176)
- Series VII: Audio
  Series VII consists of audio recordings related to Paul Langland's performances, largely of his own choreography and from his time performing with Meredith Monk's company.
  Series VII is arranged chronologically. Undated material is arranged alphabetically following the dated material.
  Access copies for audio items do not not exist at this time. Please contact a Fales Archivist.
  - Martin Luther King Jr. Center, June 8 1977 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0252)
    Audio materials have not been preserved and are not currently available to researchers.
  - Mount Carmel Baptist Church Seniors Club, June 15, 1977 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0253)
    Format: Audiocassette
  - Side A: C. Pandal Workshop, November 8, 1983 Side B: Candle Dance (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0254)
  - Dance Class, 108 Wooster, December 18, 1984 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0255)
  - J. Swaggart, Drugs, Gays, Rapture, Ultimatum, December 5, 1985 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0256)
  - Improvising with David Darline, I: Melodic Improvisation and Rhythmic Improvisation, 1987 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0257)
  - Sade A: Bix Bidebeck Side B: Danny and Paul, March 9, 1988 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0258)
  - Danny and Paul, January 1990 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0259)
  - Danny and Paul Rehersals, April 1990 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0260)
  - Side A: Danny and Paul, February 10, 1990 Side B: Danny and Paul, March 6, [1990], February 10, 1990; March 6, [1990] (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0261)
  - Danny and Paul, Jonah Duet, July 1990 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0262)
  - Interview with Paul Langland on Allan Wayne, August 25, 1996 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0263)
  - Interview with Paul Langland on Allan Wayne - Part Two, August 25, 1996 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0264)
  - Tape for Paul langland by DJ Ganesha Del Mar, January 31, 1997 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0265)
  - AAt Talks on Theater School and Scottish Bagpipes, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0266)
  - Bo's Entrance, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0267)
  - Boneyard, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0268)
  - Breathing Clicks, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0269)
  - Cherry or Cherries, Chery's in Back, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0270)
  - Dolmen Music Solos, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0271)
  - Side A: Dolmen Music and Monk Piano Side B: Turtle Dreams, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0272)
  - Drums Effect, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0273)
  - Side A: Emotional Corridors, Beethoven Side B: Vachtumschlä, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0274)
  - Fame and Money, Success, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0275)
  - Fight Dance, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0276)
  - Side A: Ghost of a Flea and Jungle Breath Side B: Jazz, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0277)
  - Glenn and Nate, Tape 1, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0278)
  - Heart Beat, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0279)
  - Jerry Goldman War Stories: IV, In Combat, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0280)
  - Jonah, Part 1, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0281)
  - Jonah, Drone, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0282)
  - Jonah, Part 2, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0283)
  - Jonah, Dub, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0284)
  - Jungle Breath, Slow, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0285)
  - La Vien Mix, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0286)
  - Mr. Natural, Test Mix, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0287)
  - Side A: Mr. Natural, Test Mix Side B: Channel Z Intro. Music - Aboriginal, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0288)
  - Offeratory Song, End of Sermon, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0289)
  - Side A: Paul's Story of Egypt Side B: Danny and Paul Voice, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0290)
  - Phil Glass, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0291)
  - Preset Music, Before and After Show, Section 6, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0292)
  - Robert Ashley Side A: Private Parts Side B: Automatic Writing, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0293)
  - Robert Burns, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0294)
  - Rudie Berkhout, Spirit Songs, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0295)
  - Smak Mix, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0296)
  - Steps, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0297)
  - Strings, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0298)
  - Swaggart, Last Tape Rehersal Sketches, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0299)
  - Turtle Dreams, Parts 1 and 2 - Mono, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0300)
  - Turtle Dreams Cha Cha Rehersal, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0301)
  - Virgil Dance, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0302)
  - Waterfall, [Digridu], Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0303)
  - Western, #2, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0304)
  - Untitled, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0305)
  - Untitled, Undated (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0306)
- Series VIII: Vinyl Sound Recordings
  Series VIII consists of four vinyl records, including Meredith Monk's "Dolman Music" on which Paul Langland provides vocals. Paul Langland
  Series VIII is arranged chronologically.
  Access copies for vinyl records are not currently available to researchers.
  - Meredith Monk, Our Lady of Late; Minona Records, 1973 (Box 32)
  - Meredith Monk, Songs from the Hill/Tablet; Wergo, 1979 (Box 32)
  - Meredith Monk, Dolman Music; ECM, 1981 (Box 32)
  - Better an Old Demon than a New God; Giorno Poetry Records, 1984 (Box 32)
- Series IV: Data Storage, 1977-1985; undated
  Series IV consists of one data CD and 2 floppy disks. These disks include files and photographs.
  Series IV is arranged chronologically
  Access copies for data storage items are not currently available. Please contact a Fales Archivist.
  - Meredith Monk Company Photographs - CD, 1977-1985 (Box 32)
  - Files Floppy Disk, 1984 (Box 32)
  - Almost Rapture floppy disk, undated (Box 32)
- Series X: Objects
  Series X consists of two costumes and a special edition Coke bottle.
  - Costume - Hat, undated (Box 29)
  - Costume - Shirt, undated (Box 30)
  - La Mama 50th Anniversary Coke Bottle, 2011 (Box 31)
- OVERSIZE Series I: Files
  Oversize Series I is arranged alphabetically by folder title. Titles are orignial unless otherwise noted with square brackets.
  - ACDFA [American College Dance Festival Association, 1988 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Cliffs of Desperes, 1996 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Contact Improv, 1984, undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Domestic Virtue, 1988-1989 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Edinburgh Fringe, Ricky DeMarco Student Workshop, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Germany, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Letters- Paul Langland Responses, undated (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Movement Research Spring Gala, 2011 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - [Retazos/Danza Teatro], undated (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Reviews- The Other Voice, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Visual Art/Film, 1987 (Box 26, Folder 11)
- OVERSIZE Series II: Notebooks and Planners
  - Black Bound Sketchbook 1: "Anatomy for Dancers", 1974 - 1976 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Black Bound Sketchbook 2: "Contact Improvisation" and "Movement Arts Class at Senior Citizens Center", 1975 - 1976 (Box 42, Folder 2)
- OVERSIZE Series IV: Posters, Programs and Flyers
  Series IV is arranged into two subseries, reflecting Paul Langland's original organization. Subseries A is arranged by artist and Subseries B is arranged by venue. Any additional material that was not assigned an original category has been arranged alphabetically by venue, and is listed at the end of the series.
  Oversize Series IV consists of oversize posters for various dance and arts performances and events. It largely consists of material related to New York City venues from the mid 1970s through the 1990s, but also includes other localities. Included in this series is material related to many noted New York City performance spaces and groups, including Danspace, Dance Theater Workshop, LaMama, and Movement Research. Due to the nature of the type of material, many of the posters do not include a year.
  - Subseries A: Artists
    - Laurie Anderson, undated (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Bread and Puppet Theater, 1982 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Tricia Brown, 1987; undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Channel Z, 1984-1987 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Ping Chong, 1986; 1992 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Lucinda Childs, undated (Map-case 1, Folder 1)
    - Contact Improv, 1975; 1977-1979; 1983 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Ellen Fisher, undated (Map-case 1, Folder 1)
    - Simone Forti, undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Grand Union, undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Paul Langland, 1983-1984; 1986; 1988-1998; 2000; undated (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Paul Langland, undated (Map-case 1, Folder 1)
    - Daniel Lepkoff, 1979; 1989; undated (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Nina Martin, undated (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Meredith Monk, 1979; 1982; 1984; 1986; 1991 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Meredith Monk, 1998; undated (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Meredith Monk, 1985 (Map-case 1, Folder 1)
    - Mary Overlie, 1998; undated (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Steve Paxton, undated (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Stephen Petronio, undated (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Stephen Petronio, undated (Map-case 1, Folder 1)
    - Diane Torr, undated (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - David Zambrano, undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Marian Zazeela, 1981 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Subseries B: Venues
    - BAM [Brooklyn Academy of Music], 1983; 1986-1988 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Danspace, 1984-1987; 1996-1997; 1999 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Dance Theater Workshop, 1986-1988 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - La Mama, undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Movement Research, 1984; 1985; 1988; 1993; 1994 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Movement Research, 1987 (Map-case 1, Folder 1)
    - NYU Experimental Theater Wing/Tisch School of the Arts, 2009; undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - NYU Experimental Theater Wing/Tisch School of the Arts, undated (Map-case 1, Folder 1)
    - PS 122, 1981; 1984; 1988 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Whitney Museum of Art, undated (Map-case 1, Folder 1)
    - Venues A-Z, 1977; 1980-1984; 1989-1990; 1998; 2000; undated (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - General Posters
    - General Poster, undated (Map-case 1, Folder 1)
- OVERSIZE Series V: Allan Wayne Material
  Oversize Series V consists of several performance posters featuring Allan Wayne.
  - Allan Wayne Material, undated (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - [Allan Wayne- Theater Dance Poster], undated (Box 28, Folder 12)